Somebody asked me today...
今天有人我
"Phil, if you could be anywhere, where would you like to be?"
「菲，S便你x地方 你想到哪去？」
I said to him, "Probably right here."
我跟他f 「大概就是@e」
Elko, Nevada. Our nation's high at 79 today.
热A_州的艾科 今天茸罡厝A氏79度
In California, they'll have warm weather tomorrow...
加州明天有嘏的天狻
gang wars and some very overpriced real estate.
团纱螋Y和超F的房地a
Up in the Pacific Northwest, they'll have some very tall trees.
太平洋岸西北部 有很高大的洹
It will be clear across the Rockies and the Great Plains.
(l星D片) 落山}天馇缋省
But look out, here comes trouble.
不^要小心，有麻┮砹
Oh, boy! Front coming our way. Look out.
天啊！ 直接χ我而恚小心
What will that mean to us in the Three Rivers area?
那θ河地^有什N影？
One of these big blue things! This cold, frigid, Arctic air.
@一大片{色^K 是寒冷的北OF
This big mass out of the north.
谋狈淼拇笃F
It will meet up with all this moisture coming out of the Gulf...
它和碜阅西哥 的峥庀嘤
mix together at high altitudes and cause some snow.
在高海拔地^混合 然後е陆笛
It won't hit us here in Pittsburgh. It will push off and hit Altoona.
它不侵u匹堡 而抵_D{
Close call.
好U
Let's take a look at the five-day.
我砜次砦逄斓 天忸Ay
Nothing to be too scared about.
]什N好心的
Bundle up warm, but leave your galoshes at home.
穿得暖和一c 可是不必穿雨靴
I won't be here for the 10:00.
十c我不在@e
Tomorrow is Groundhog Day, and I'm going out to Punxsutawney...
明天是土苁蠊
for our country's oldest groundhog festival.
⒓尤v史最久的 土苁蠊c
According to the legend, tomorrow, February 2...
根髡f，明天2月2日
if the groundhog sees his shadow, we'll have six more weeks of winter.
如果土苁罂吹阶约旱挠白 冬天就有六周
- Keep your fingers crossed. - Sounds like a lot of fun.
- 祈求好\吧 - 好像很好玩的幼
This is your third year in a row isn't it?
@是你Bm第三年去吧？
Four, Nan.
第四年
Thanks, Phil.
xx你，菲
Up next: Diane Kingman looks at sex and violence in the movies.
接下恚黛安金曼 要探影中的性c暴力
Stay with us.
不要走_
- We're clear. - Have fun in Punxsutawney.
- 好了 - 到普K塔尼玩得愉快
For your information, Hairdo...
告V你，美l妹
there is a major network interested in me.
有家o台ξ矣信d趣
That would be the Home Shopping Network.
一定是物l道
Thanks, Larry. Go wait in the van.
x了，瑞，到上等
That was nice. "Big trees."
f得真妙，「高大的洹
Stop, Henny. Can you handle the 10:00 or not?
]嘴，亨利 你能不能笫c的庀螅
If you don't want to rush back, I can do the 5:00 tomorrow.
如果你不想太s的 我可以竺魈煳妩c那
I want to stay an extra second in Punxsutawney? Please!
我在普K塔尼多待一秒？ e[了！
Rita thinks it would be great to stay for some of the other events...
塔X得留在那 ⒓e的活雍懿诲e
get some incredible footage.
可以拍一些很棒的R^
The people and the fun, the excitement.
群、g愤有刺激
You haven't worked with her yet. She's really nice.
你]跟她共事^，她人很好
She's gonna be a really good producer.
她是很好的u作人
You guys will have fun.
你很_心的
She's fun, but not my kind of fun. I will be here for the 5:00. Rita.
她的_心和我的不一 我五c恚塔
Can you keep a secret, Larry?
可以臀冶Ｃ幔瑞？
I'm probably leaving PBH.
我可能x_PBH
So this will be the last time we do the Groundhog together.
@是我最後一次 一起土苁蠊
What's wrong with the Groundhog Festival?
土苁蠊有什N不好？
In San Diego, I covered the swallows returning to Capistrano six years.
我在}地牙哥 燕子返回卡皮卓Z六年
Someday somebody will see me interviewing a groundhog...
有一天有人看到 我在L土苁
and think I don't have a future.
我根本]有前途
I think it's a nice story.
那是很好的
He comes out, and he looks around.
它爬出恚四看看
He wrinkles up his little nose. He sees his shadow or he doesn't see it.
起小鼻子 到底有]有看到影子呢
It's nice. People like it.
很棒，^喜g
You are new, aren't you?
你是新淼陌桑
People like blood sausage too.
^也喜g血香c
People are morons.
^是白V
Nice attitude.
你的B度真不e
Look in the mirror and see what you look like doing that groundhog thing.
照照R子，看你土苁蠊 是什N德性
For me? Once?
做一次o我看
He comes out and looks at his little shadow.
它爬出恚看到自己的影子
- Would you like some blood sausage? - I like blood sausage.
- 要睃c血香c幔 - 我喜g血香c
Rita, I can't stay here.
塔，我不能住在@e
- Prima donna. - I'll handle it. What's the matter?
- 真y搞 - 我硖理，怎N回事？
I hate this place. I stayed here two years ago. I was miserable.
我@地方 我2年前就磉^，r好K
- It's a fleabag. I'm not staying here. - You're not staying here.
- @根本是狗C，我不要住在 @e     - 你不用住在@e
I'm not?
- 不用幔 - Π
Larry's dropping me off. I booked you in a nice bed-and-breakfast.
瑞只是我下 我湍阌了很棒的旅^
Great. I think this is the trait of a really good producer:
很好 @是秀u作人必涞奶攸c
Keep the talent happy.
明星_心
Anything I can do.
我很芬庑
Would you help me with my pelvic tilt?
意服侍我上所幔
Within reason.
e得寸M尺
Would you like to have dinner with Larry and me?
你要和我跟瑞吃晚餐幔
No, thank you. I've seen Larry eat.
不，xx 我看^瑞吃的德性
Get your sleep. I'll see you in the morning.
去睡X吧，明天早上
Don't be late.
et到
Did he actually call himself"the talent"?
他真的自Q椤该餍恰幔
Okay, campers, rise and shine.
起床了
Don't forget your booties because it's cold out there today.
e忘了你的b 今天外面很冷
It's cold out there every day. What is this, Miami Beach?
外面每天都很冷 y道@e是~阿密海幔
Not hardly. You can expect hazardous travel later with that blizzard thing.
不可能，等一下你就 可以在大L雪中冒U了
"That blizzard thing"? Here's the report.
「大L雪」？ 接下硎庀蟾
The National Weather Service is calling for a big blizzard thing.
庀缶终f有大L雪
They are. But there's another reason why today is especially exciting.
Γ不^今天特e刺激 有一原因
Especially cold.
天馓e冷
The big question on everybody's lips...
每人唇 都冒出一大}
On their chapped lips.
裂的嘴唇
Do you think Phil will come out and see his shadow?
你想菲出看到影子幔
- Punxsutawney Phil. - That's right, woodchuck chuckers.
- 普K塔尼菲 - ]e，土苁笸妒
It's Groundhog Day!
今天是土苁蠊！
- Get up and check that hog! - Come here, groundhog!
- 起砜赐苁蟀桑 - ^恚土苁
Good morning.
早安
- You off to see the groundhog? - I am.
- 你去看土苁幔 -
Do you think it will be an early spring?
今年是早春幔
I'm predicting March 21.
我Ay是3月21日
Good guess.
猜得好
I think that actually is the first day of spring.
我想那是春天的第一天
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
睡得好幔康{先生？
I slept alone, Mrs. Lancaster.
我一人睡，{太太
- Would you like some coffee? - Is there any possibility...
- 想喝咖啡幔 - 今天早上
of getting an espresso or a cappuccino this morning?
有]有饪s咖啡或卡布奇Z？
I really don't know.
我真的不知道…
How to spell "espresso" or "cappuccino."
「饪s咖啡」或「卡布奇Z」 怎N拼？
This looks fine.
@就可以了
- I hope you enjoy the festivities. - I'm sure I will.
- 祝你@次玩得愉快 - 一定的
There's talk of a blizzard.
f有大L雪
We may catch a break and have that blizzard blow by us.
天有化 大L雪被吹走
All this moisture coming up out of the south...
@股哪戏淼峥
will probably push on east of us.
可能吹到我的|
At high altitudes it will crystallize and give us what we call snow.
它在高海拔地^Y晶 槲斫笛
Probably will be some accumulation...
可能有e雪
but here in Punxsutawney our high will be about 30 today, teens tonight.
不^今天普K塔尼最高 _到A氏30度，晚上有十锥
Chance of precipitation about 20 percent today and tomorrow.
今明商伢E降的C率 大s20%
Did you want to talk about the weather or were you just making chitchat?
你是想天膺是在f聊？
- Chitchat. - See you later.
- f聊 - 回^
- Bye. - Will you be checking out today?
- 再 - 你今天退房幔
Chance of departure today: 100 percent.
今天x_的C率是100%
Phil Connors? I thought that was you!
菲康{？我就知道是你！
How you doing? Thanks for watching.
你好幔恐xx^p
Don't tell me you don't remember me. I sure as heck-fire remember you.
ef你不得我 我可是得很清楚喔
- Not a chance. - Ned Ryerson!
- 想不起 - 尼德R森
Needlenose Ned. Ned the Head.
尖鼻子尼德、d^尼德
Come on, buddy. Case Western High.
少砹耍老兄，西P高中
I did the whistling belly button trick at the high school talent show. Bing!
我表演^肚吹口哨，乒！
Got the shingles real bad senior year, almost didn't graduate.
高三得了乐氐畎疹 差c不了I
Bing again!
乒！
I dated your sister Mary Pat till you told me not to anymore.
我跟你妹莉s^ 直到你阻止我橹
Did you turn pro with that belly button thing or what?
你後砼苋ケ硌 I肚皮秀了幔
- I sell insurance. - What a shock.
- 我在拉保U - 令人震@
Do you have life insurance? You could always use a little more.
你有保垭U幔 Sr都能再多I一份喔
Am I right or am I right or am I right? Right?
ΣΓΣΓ
I would love to stand here and talk with you, but I'm not going to.
我很想站在@e跟你聊 可是我不行
- See you. - I'll walk with you.
- 再 - 我陪你走
Whenever I see an opportunity now, I charge it like a bull.
我只要遇到C 就像牛一泳o追不放
Ned the Bull, that's me now.
我F在是猛牛尼德
I have friends who live and die by the actuarial tables.
我有朋友靠保U金l
It's all one big crap shoot.
在很走\
Have you ever heard of single premium life?
你^一次UK身保U幔
I think that really could be the ticket for you.
非常m合你
God! It is so good to see you!
天啊！到你真高d！
- What are you doing for dinner? - Something else.
- 你晚餐rg有什N？ - 我有事
It's been great seeing you, Needlehead. Take care.
到你真好 尖^，保重
Watch out for that first step. It's a doozy!
小心那一步，很重要！
Strike up the music The band has begun
奏起音罚逢_始演奏
The Pennsylvania Polka
e州波卡舞曲
Pick out your partner and join in the fun
邀你的夥伴一起硗
It started in Scranton It's now number one
它起源自史坎D F在已是第一名
It's gonna entertain you
人_心o比
Where have you been?
你到哪去了？
It was horrible. A giant leech got me.
好可怕，我被一l大水蛭p上
You're missing all the fun. These people are great.
你e^了很好玩的|西 @些人太棒了
Some have been partying all night. They sing until they get too cold...
有人匾箍g 一直唱到冷得受不了
then they sit by the fire, get warm and sing some more.
然後就坐在火堆旁取暖 又^m唱歌
They're hicks, Rita.
他是l下人，塔
Did you sleep okay without me? You tossed and turned, didn't you?
]有我你睡得好幔 是不是Dy眠？
- You're incredible. - Who told you?
- 你太xV了 - lf的？
It's groundhog time.
土苁rg到了
On me in three.
倒担3…
Two, one.
2、1
Once a year, the eyes of the nation turn to this tiny Pennsylvania hamlet...
每年此r，全的焦c
to watch a master at work.
想看一名大工作的情形
The master? Punxsutawney Phil...
@位大就是普K塔尼的菲
the world's most famous weatherman, the groundhog...
全球最著名的庀箢AT
who, as legend has it, can predict the coming of an early spring.
髡f它能A言早春的降R
The question we have to ask ourselves today is, "Does Phil feel lucky?"
今天我要自的}是
Then it's the same old schtick.
然後又是同拥睦习
The guy with the big stick raps on the door.
拿著大棍子的砘锴瞄T
They pull the little rat out. They talk to him.
把那b老鼠抱出 跟它f
The rat talks back and then they tell us what's gonna happen.
老鼠回答他 然後他就fl生什N事
Isn't he cute?
它很可郯桑
You like your guys with prominent upper teeth?
你喜g男友有暴牙幔
"This February 2, at 7:20 and 30 seconds...
今年2月2日 7c20分30秒
Punxsutawney Phil, the seer of seers...
普K塔尼的菲 先知中的先知
prognosticator of prognosticators...
A言家中的A言家
emerged reluctantly, but alertly...
很不情地出F在
in Punxsutawney, Pennsylvania...
e州的普K塔尼
and stated in Groundhogese...
它用土苁笳Zf
'I definitely see a shadow."'
「我看到了影子」
Sorry, folks. Six more weeks of winter.
抱歉，各位 冬天有六周
On me in three. Two, one.
倒3、2、1
Television really fails to capture the true excitement...
]k法捕捉到 一b大松鼠…
of a large squirrel predicting the weather.
Ay天獾恼d^感
I, for one, am very grateful to have been here.
我很感激能到@e
From Punxsutawney, this is Phil Connors. So long.
菲康{在普K塔尼的 再
Want to try it again without the sarcasm?
想用不S刺的方式 再一次幔
We got it. I'm out of here.
拍完了，我要走了
Prima donnas.
真y搞
Boy, take a look at this.
你看看
- What is going on? - I don't know.
- 怎N回事？ - 我不知道
Perhaps it's that giant blizzard we're not supposed to get.
也S是我不遇到的大L雪
This is impossible.
不可能
Nobody honks this horn but me, pal.
只有我才能按喇叭
Take this rig out of here.
把子拖走
Commander, what's going on?
警官，怎N回事？
There's nothing going on. We're closing the road.
]事，要封]路面
- Big blizzard moving in. - What blizzard? It's a couple flakes.
- 大L雪逼近了 - 什NL雪？只是雪花而已
Don't you listen to the weather? We got a major storm here.
你]庀箢A幔 @e有大L暴
I make the weather!
我是庀蟮模
All this moisture coming up out of the Gulf...
哪西哥淼峥
will push off to the east and hit Altoona.
往|移，侵uD{
Pal, you got that moisture on your head.
老兄，你^上有雪
You can go back to Punxsutawney or you can freeze to death.
不回普K塔尼就鏊涝谶@e
It's your choice. What's it gonna be?
看你的x瘢怎N樱
I'm thinking.
我在想
All the long-distance lines are down?
所有L途路都不通？
What about the satellite? Is it snowing in space?
l星呢？太空中也下雪幔
Don't you have a line you keep open for emergencies or for celebrities?
y道]有路_放 供o急r或名人使用幔
I'm both. I'm a celebrity in an emergency.
我烧叨际 我是l生o急r的名人
Can you patch me through on that line, please?
臀医油ê幔
Can I have one more with booze in it?
可以再肀酒幔
I like it here.
我好喜g@e
Phil, are you going to the groundhog dinner?
菲，你⒓油苁 晚餐幔
I had groundhog for lunch. It wasn't bad.
我午餐吃了土苁 味道不e
Tastes like chicken. You two run along.
M像u肉的，你去吧
Looking foxy tonight, man.
今晚很喔
Is your troop selling cookies again this year?
你的童子 今年再u幔
That's so funny, Phil.
真好笑，菲
What are you gonna do?
你要做什N？
I'm going back to my room and take a hot shower.
回房g洗崴澡
Maybe read Hustler or something.
f不定看看w请sI
Suit yourself.
S便你
God!
天啊
Yo, Mom. Isn't there any hot water?
老，]有崴幔
There wouldn't be today.
今天]有
Of course not. Silly me.
然]有，我真笨
Sweet dreams.
祝你好
Nice going, boys. You're playing yesterday's tape.
做的好，小子 你播的是昨天的ё
Chapped lips.
裂的嘴唇
What the hell?
怎N搞的？
Good morning. Off to see the groundhog?
早安，要去看土苁幔
Think it will be an early spring?
今年是早春幔
Didn't we do this yesterday?
我昨天^了吧？
I don't know what you mean.
我不懂你的意思
Don't mess with me, Pork Chop.
e耍我啊，胖i
- What day is this? - It's February 2. Groundhog Day.
- 今天滋？ - 2月2日土苁蠊
I thought it was yesterday.
我以槭亲蛱
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
睡得好幔康{先生？
Did I sleep well?
睡得好幔
- Would you like some coffee? - Please. I think I'll have a double.
- 想喝c咖啡幔 - 好，我要p份的
I hope you enjoy the festivities.
祝你玩得_心
There's talk of a blizzard.
f有大L雪
Do you ever have deja vu?
你有 「似曾相R」的感X幔
I don't think so, but I could check with the kitchen.
]有，但我可以N房
That's okay. Thank you.
]PS，xx
Will you be checking out today?
你今天要退房幔
I'd say the chance of departure is 80 percent.
我x_的C率是80%
Seventy-five, eighty.
75，80
Excuse me.
Σ黄
Where is everybody going?
大家要去哪？
To Gobbler's Knob. It's Groundhog Day.
去火u丘，今天是土苁蠊
It's still just once a year, isn't it?
那是一年一次吧？
Phil Connors. I thought that was you.
菲康{，我就知道是你
Don't you say you don't remember me. I sure as heck-fire remember you.
ef你不得我 我可是得很清楚喔
Ned Ryerson?
尼德R森？
Bing! First shot right out of the box!
乒！一猜就中！
How's it going, old buddy?
你好幔老兄？
Actually, I'm not feeling well. Would you excuse me?
我不太舒服，失陪了
It's funny you should mention your health.
真有趣，竟然你提到你的健康
You will never guess what I do now.
你^Σ虏坏轿易瞿囊恍
- Do you sell insurance? - Bing again!
- 拉保U幔 - 又猜中了
You are sharp as a tack today.
你今天真明
Do you have life insurance? If you do, you could always use more.
你有垭U幔咳绻有 可以多I一c
Right? Who couldn't?
Π桑空l不是呢？
You know something? I got a feeling you ain't got any.
我感X到你]有保U
- Am I right or am I right? - I gotta go.
- ΣΓ - 我要走了
Watch out for that first step. It's a doozy.
小心那一步，很重要
- Where have you been? - Rita, do me a favor.
- 你到哪去了？ - 塔，臀乙忙
I need someone to give me a good hard slap in the face.
我需要有人p我一巴掌
- How's that? - Good.
- 怎N樱 - 很好
If you need help with the other cheek, let me know. I'm right here.
右也需要的通知我哦 Sr奉陪
- Something's going on. - Are you drunk or something?
- 不太 - 你是喝醉了是怎樱
Drunk's more fun. Can I be serious for a minute?
喝醉有趣多了 我能烂C一分幔
- I don't know. Can you? - I'm being serious.
- 我不知道，你能幔 - 我F在很烂C
I'm having a problem. I may be having a problem.
我有}了，可能有}了
- It's groundhog time. - I knew you would say that.
- 土苁rg到了 - 我就知道你那Nf
I really feel weird.
我真的X得很奇怪
Let's just do this, then we'll talk.
我先拍完再
On me in three.
倒3…
Two, one.
2、1
It's Groundhog Day again.
土苁蠊又到了
That must mean we're at Gobbler's Knob waiting for the forecast...
我一定在火u丘等待
from the world's most famous groundhog weatherman...
全球最著名的土苁箢AT
Punxsutawney Phil...
普K塔尼菲
who's just about to tell us how much more winter we can expect.
它⒏嬖V我冬天有多久
This is a riot.
好狒[哦
Isn't he cute?
它很可郯桑
Yeah, Sport, I know there's a blizzard.
Γ老兄，我知道有大L雪
When are the long-distance lines gonna be repaired?
L途路何r修好？
What if there is no tomorrow? There wasn't one today.
f一]有明天呢？ 今天就]有啊
Hello?
喂？
Good morning. Off to see the groundhog?
早安，要去看土苁幔
Did you sleep well, Mr...
睡得好幔康…
I thought...
我就知道…
Don't say you don't remember me. I sure as heck-fire remember you.
ef你不得我 我可是得很清楚喔
It's me, Ned Ryerson!
是我，尼德R森！
Needlenose Ned. Ned the Head. Come on, buddy. Case Western...
尖鼻子尼德，d^尼德 老兄，西P…
- Where have you been? - Can we talk about a nonwork matter?
- 你到哪去了？ - c工作以外的事好幔
- You never talk about work. - We really have to talk. Come on.
- 你聿徽工作 - 我真的需要，
- It's a creative meeting. Forget it. - Wait a second. We've got work to do.
- @是意h，e想跟 - 等等，我有工作要做
I don't. I've already done it twice.
我]有，我已做^纱瘟
When you get finished, meet me in the diner.
等你拍完，跟我在餐d碰面
- What's that all about? - I don't know.
- 怎N回事？ - 不知道
Prima donnas.
很y搞
More coffee, hon?
要咖啡幔
No, thanks. Just the check, please.
不，x了，I
- These sticky buns are heaven. - Aren't they?
- 甜c真可口 - 那然
Just put that anywhere, pal.
S便放
Good save.
救得好
Tell me why you're too sick to work, and it better be good.
你怎病到不能工作 最好理由好一c
I'm reliving the same day over and over.
我不嘀馗步v同一天
Groundhog Day. Today.
土苁蠊，今天
I'm waiting for the punch line.
我在等你的理由
Really. This is the third time.
真的，@是第三次了
It's like yesterday never happened.
就像昨天根本]有l生^
I am racking my brain, but I can't imagine why you'd make this up.
我一直不懂 你楹尉@故事呢
I'm not making it up. I am asking you for help!
我]有，我在求你的兔
What do you want me to do?
你要我怎N做？
I don't know! You're a producer, come up with something.
我不知道，你是u作人 想想k法
You want my advice?
想我的建h幔
You should get your head examined if you expect me to believe that story.
要我相信你的f法的 最好去z查你的X袋，菲
Like the groundhog Phil?
你和土苁蠓同名？
Look out for your shadow, pal.
找找你的影子，老兄
Morons, your bus is leaving.
白V，你的公要走了
You guys ready? We better get going...
好了幔刻庾闹前 最好s快x_
I'm not going back to Pittsburgh.
我不要回匹堡
- Why not? - Because of the blizzard.
- 槭颤N？ - 因橛写箫L雪
You said that would hit Altoona.
你f它侵uD{
I know that's what I said.
我知道我是那Nf
I think you need help.
我想你需要兔
That's what I've been saying. I need help.
我也一直f我需要兔
No spots, no clots...
]有斑c、血K
no tumors, no lesions...
]有[瘤、C能障K
no aneurisms.
]有用}瘤
None that I can see.
我看]什N}
If you want a CAT scan or an MRI, you have to go into Pittsburgh.
想做呙榛虼殴舱 就得回匹堡
I can't go into Pittsburgh.
我]k法回匹堡
- Why can't you go into Pittsburgh? - There's a blizzard.
- 槭颤N？ - 有大L雪
Right. The blizzard.
Γ大L雪
You know what you may need, Mr. Connors?
知道你需要什N 康{先生？
A biopsy.
切片z查
A psychiatrist.
精神科t生
That's an unusual problem, Mr. Connors.
@是很不こ５}
Most of my work is with couples, families.
我的病人大多是夫妻、一家人
I have an alcoholic now.
F在有一酒鬼
You went to college, right? It wasn't veterinary psychology, was it?
你上^大W吧？ 不是念Ft心理W吧？
Didn't you take some course that covered this stuff?
你有]有修^跟@有P的n？
Sort of. I guess.
算有吧
Abnormal psychology.
B心理W
So, what do I do?
我怎Nk？
I think we should meet again.
你再
How's tomorrow for you?
明天可以幔
Is that not good?
不好幔
I was in the Virgin Islands once.
我有一次去S京群u
I met a girl.
遇到一女孩子
We ate lobster, drank pina coladas.
我一起吃r、喝u尾酒
At sunset, we made love like sea otters.
S昏r我像海H一幼
That was a pretty good day.
那真是美好的一天
Why couldn't I get that day over and over and over?
我楹尾荒芊锤策^那一天？
You know, some guys would look at this glass...
有些人看到@玻璃杯子
and they would say, "That glass is half empty."
他f「@杯子半空」
Other guys would say, "That glass is half full."
其他人f「@杯子半M」
I peg you as a "glass is half empty" kind of guy. Am I right?
我J槟闶恰赴肟铡剐偷娜 ΣΓ
What would you do if you were stuck in one place...
如果你困在一地方 每天都完全一
and every day was exactly the same, and nothing that you did mattered?
做什N都改不了r 你怎Nk？
That sums it up for me.
我的人生就是那
Good luck. I'll drop you off.
祝你好\，我半路你下
- This thing sticks. You gotta jiggle it. - Come on up here.
- 卡住了，要u一下 - 起
- My gosh. - Give me your keys, pal.
- 天啊 - 匙o我
Friends don't let friends drive. Stand up here. Take a deep breath.
是朋友就不你_ 站好，深呼吸
You feel okay? Really?
你好幔空娴模
You're all right.
你]事了
You want to throw up here or in the car?
想在@e是上吐？
- I think both. - Come on.
- 都要 - 戆
I don't think I should be driving.
我不_
I don't either. Watch your head.
我想也是，小心^
Watch your knees. Don't break anything.
小心膝w，e受了
All right. Let's not forget seat belts.
好，e忘了系安全
Who else could go for some flapjacks right now?
有l能去I煎？
Let me ask you guys a question.
我你一}
- Shoot. - What if there were no tomorrow?
- f吧 - f一]有明天呢？
No tomorrow? That would mean there would be no consequences.
]有明天？也就是]有Y果_
There would be no hangovers. We could do whatever we wanted!
不有宿醉 我可以S心所欲！
That's true. We could do whatever we want.
]e，想做什N就做什N
If we wanted to hit mailboxes, we could let Ralph drive!
要是想撞]筒 就雷夫_了
- I think they want you to stop. - Hang on.
- 我想他要你停 - 抓好
It's the same thing your whole life:
人生就是@N一回事
"Clean up your room." " Stand up straight." " Pick up your feet."
「清理房g」、「站好」 「_抬起怼
"Take it like a man." "Be nice to your sister."
「像男人有」 「δ忝煤靡稽c」
"Don't mix beer and wine, ever."
「e把啤酒和葡萄酒混合」
"Don't drive on the railroad tracks."
「e在F上_」
Phil, that's one I happen to agree with.
菲，@c我好同意
I don't know, Gus.
我不知道，Z斯
Sometimes I think you just have to take the big chances.
我想有r候就孤注一S
This is the police! Pull over immediately!
我是警察！立刻停
We're talking in here.
我在f
I'm betting he'll swerve first.
我猜他先D
I'm not gonna live by their rules anymore.
我不要再照e人的t生活了
- I noticed that. - You make choices and live with them.
- 我注意到了 - 做了x窬鸵接受
My knee.
我的膝w
Let me handle this.
我付
Three cheeseburgers, two large fries...
三吉士h堡，煞荽笫l
two chocolate shakes and one large Coke.
杀巧克力奶昔 有一杯大可
- And some flapjacks. - Too early for flapjacks?
- 有煎 - 吃煎太早了幔
Rise and shine, campers!
快起床！
Don't forget your booties because it's cold out there today!
e忘了b洌今天外面很冷
It's cold out there every day. What is this, Miami Beach? Not hardly.
外面每天都很冷 @e是~阿密海幔坎豢赡
Slept like a baby. Thank you.
睡得像阂樱xx
- I'd love some of your coffee. - I hope...
- 我想睃c咖啡 - 你想…
Flurries moving in later, but the blizzard will hit outside of town.
晚一c下雪 不^大L雪侵u城外
Mrs. Lancaster, was anybody looking for me here this morning?
{太太 今天早上有人找我幔
Perhaps a state official? Maybe a blue hat, gun, nightstick?
也S是戴{帽、佩 有警棍的州警？
No one like that. Will there be?
]有那N人，有幔
Apparently not.
@然]有
Hold my room for me, please. I'm staying an extra day.
臀冶Ａ舴块g 我要多待一天
Catch you tomorrow, Pops.
明天，老爹
I like to see a man of advancing years throwing caution to the wind.
我喜g看上了年o的人 暴暴食
It's inspiring, in a way.
U激钊诵牡
My years are not advancing as fast as you might think.
我]你想的那N老
More coffee, hon?
要咖啡幔
Just keep it coming, please.
拿^
Sure thing.
好
Just put that anywhere, pal.
S便放
Good save.
救得好
Don't you worry about cholesterol, lung cancer, love handles?
你不心固醇、肺癌幔
I don't worry about anything anymore.
我什N都不心了
What makes you so special? Everybody worries about something.
你怎N@N特e？ 大家有事心
That's exactly what makes me so special. I don't even have to floss.
所以我才特e 我甚至都不用牙剔牙
What?
怎樱
"The wretch, concentered all in self...
「可z的人只注意自己」
Living, shall forfeit fair renown...
「生活，适名」
And, doubly dying, shall go down...
「而p重的死亡 乃出F的地方」
To the vile dust, from whence he sprung...
「落到污x的m埃中」
Unwept, unhonor'd, and unsung."
「o人哀悼、尊崇、歌」
Sir Walter Scott.
A特史考特爵士的
- You don't like poetry? - I love poetry.
- 你不喜g？ - 我很墼
I just thought that was Willard Scott. I was confused.
我以槭峭勒史考特 我都搞糊T了
Do you think I'm acting like this because I'm egocentric?
你想我@ 是因樘自我中心幔
I know you're egocentric. It's your defining characteristic.
我知道你很自我中心 那是你的特c
Are you guys ready? We better get going to stay ahead of the weather.
你好了]？ 趁天]那摆s快出l
Thanks, Larry. Would you like a doggie bag?
x了，瑞 需要打包幔
- I'll stay here and finish. - I thought you hated this town.
- 我留在@e吃完 - 我以槟悴幌g@e
It's beginning to grow on me.
我越碓较g@e了
Larry, quit staring.
瑞，e再看了
These are excellent.
吃@，@很好吃
Did you see the groundhog this morning?
今天早上有看到土苁幔
I never miss it.
我牟诲e^
What's your name?
你F姓大名？
Nancy Taylor. And you are?
南茜泰勒，你是？
- What high school did you go to? - What?
- 你上哪所高中？ - 什N？
- High school. - Lincoln, in Pittsburgh.
- 高中 - 林肯高中，在匹堡
- Who are you? - Who was your senior English teacher?
- 你是l？ - 你高三的英文老是l？
Are you kidding?
你在_玩笑幔
- Your 12th-grade English teacher was... - Mrs. Walsh.
- 你高三的英文老是… - AS老
Nancy. Lincoln. Walsh. Thanks very much.
南茜，林肯，AS xx
Lincoln High School.
林肯高中
I sat next to you in Mrs. Walsh's English class.
AS老的n我坐你隔壁
I'm sorry.
Σ黄稹
- That's amazing. - You don't remember me, do you?
- 好巧 - 你不得我了吧？
I even asked you to the prom.
我邀你⒓赢I舞
I was short, and I've sprouted.
r我很矮，後黹L高了
Gosh! How are you?
天啊，你好幔
Great. You look terrific.
很好，你看起砻O了
You look very terrific.
直美呆了
- I have to do this report. - Are you a reporter?
- 我得做@ - 你是者？
I'm a weatherman with Channel 9 Pittsburgh.
我是匹堡第9l道的 庀蟛T
I should have known. That's great!
我早知道，太好了！
Maybe later we could...
或S晚一c我可以…
Whatever.
什N都好
Stay right here. Promise me?
待在@e，答我？
I'll be right back. Wish me luck.
我R上回恚祝我好\
Good luck!
祝你好\！
Who's Rita?
l是塔？
How should I know?
我怎N知道？
Is this some kind of one-night stand?
@算什N？一夜情幔
On the contrary, Nancy. I love you.
好相反，南茜 我勰
I've always loved you.
我一直壑你
This is gonna seem sudden, but...
@Nf很突然，但是…
Nancy, will you be my wife?
南茜，你意我的老婆幔
Whatever.
S便啦
A gust of wind.
一L吹^
A dog barks.
狗_始叫
Cue the truck.
卡M
Exit Herman.
赫曼走出
Walk into the bank.
(北方邦π钽y行) 走My行
Exit Felix. Stand there with a not-so-bright look on your face.
菲力走出恚色不太好
All right, Doris, come on.
桃莉出
Fix your bra, honey. That's better.
{整一下胸罩，甜心 @雍枚嗔
"Felix." "How you doing, Doris?"
「菲力」 「你好幔桃莉？」
"Can I have a roll of quarters?"
「Q一卷2毛5硬藕幔俊
Ten, nine, eight...
10、9、8
Car. Six, five...
子、6、5
Quarters.
硬
- What? - Did I bring out two bags or one?
- 怎樱 - 我拿纱是一袋出恚
I don't know.
不知道
I thought we were going to a costume party.
我以橐⒓踊b派
It's like I said, I love this film.
就像我f的，我圻@部影
I've seen it over a hundred times.
我看^一百多遍了
I told you to call me Bronco.
叫我布朗柯
Sorry, Bronco.
Σ黄穑布朗柯
My old fiance. They never remember me.
我以前的未婚妻 她是不得我
- That will be one adult and... - Two adults.
- 一全票和… - 全票
The question we have to ask ourselves today is, "Does Phil feel lucky?"
今天我要自的}是 「菲X得\馊绾危俊
Rita, if you only had one day to live, what would you do with it?
塔，如果你的生命只剩一天 你怎N^？
I don't know, Phil. What are you dying of?
我不知道，菲 你要死了幔
I mean, the whole world is about to explode. What do you do?
不…假如地球快爆炸了 你怎Nk？
I want to know where to put the camera.
我只想知道z影C要放哪
Are you looking for a date for the weekend?
你在找L末的sο幔
I'm just interested in you.
我δ阌信d趣
What do you want? What do you like? What do you think about?
你要什N？你喜g什N？ 你在想什N？
What kind of men are you interested in?
你δ姆N男人有d趣？
What do you do for fun?
你做什N消遣？
Is this for real or are you trying to make me look like a fool?
你是f真的，是想捉弄我？
I'm just trying to talk like normal people talk. Isn't this how they talk?
我只想像一般人那诱f 他不是@诱f的幔
- Close. - So talk to me.
- 差不多 - 那就跟我f
Let me buy you a cup of coffee.
我你喝杯咖啡
- And a donut. - All right.
- 加上一甜甜圈 - 好
What do you want out of life?
你想纳活中得到什N？
I guess I want what everybody wants:
我要每人都想要的
Career, love, marriage, children.
事I、矍椤⒒橐觥⒑⒆
Are you seeing anyone?
你F在有ο幔
I think this is getting too personal.
@}太[私了
I don't think I'm ready to share this with you.
我不涓你分享@些
How about you? What do you want?
你呢？你要什N？
What I really want is someone like you.
我想要的是你@拥娜
- Please. - Why not?
- 拜 - 有什N不可以？
What are you looking for? Who is your perfect guy?
你在追な颤N？ 你的理想ο褚怎樱
First of all, he's too humble to know he's perfect.
首先，他很t 明白自己不蛲昝
That's me.
我就是@
He's intelligent, supportive, funny.
明、支持我、幽默
Me, me, me.
我、我、我
- He's romantic and courageous. - Me also.
- 浪漫而且勇敢 - 我也是
He's got a good body, but doesn't look in the mirror every two minutes.
他身材很好 但不]事猛照R子
I have a great body, and sometimes I go months without looking.
我身材很棒 有r月都不照R子
He's kind, sensitive and gentle.
他善良、wN又厝
He's not afraid to cry in front of me.
不怕在我面前哭
This is a man, right?
他是男人吧？
He likes animals and children, and he'll change poopy diapers.
他喜g游锖托『 Q有大便的尿布
Does he have to use the word "poopy"?
一定要用「大便」@字眼幔
And he plays an instrument, and he loves his mother.
他奏菲鳎鬯的母H
I am really close on this one.
我真的和@人很相近
It's Phil Connors.
他是菲康{
Hello. Thanks for watching.
xx^p
So, what are the chances of getting out today?
今天x_的C率有多大？
The van still won't start. Larry's working on it.
子是l不 瑞正在想k法
Wouldn't you know it. Can I buy you a drink?
l知道怎 你喝杯酒好幔
Jim Beam, ice, water.
金e威士忌，加冰K，加水
For you, miss?
你呢，小姐？
Sweet vermouth on the rocks with a twist, please.
甜苦艾酒加冰K，放檬片
What are the chances of getting out of town today?
今天出城的C率有多大？
The van still won't start. Larry's working on it.
子是l不 瑞正在想k法
Wouldn't you know it. Can I buy you a drink?
l知道怎 你喝杯酒好幔
Sweet vermouth, rocks with a twist, please.
甜苦艾酒加冰K，放檬片
- For you, miss? - The same.
- 你呢，小姐？ - 一
- That's my favorite drink. - Mine too.
- 那是我最酆鹊木 - 我也是
It always makes me think of Rome, the way the sun hits the buildings.
它我想到_R 光⒃诮êB物上的幼
What shall we drink to?
我要敬什N？
To the groundhog.
敬土苁
I always drink to world peace.
我都敬世界和平
Can I buy you a drink?
你喝杯酒好幔
Sweet vermouth, rocks with a twist, please.
甜苦艾酒加冰K，放檬片
For you, miss?
你呢，小姐？
The same. That's my favorite drink.
一樱那是我最鄣木
Mine too.
我也是
It always makes me think of Rome...
它我想到_R
the way the sun hits the buildings.
光⒃诮êB物上的幼
What shall we drink to?
我要敬什N？
I like to say a prayer and drink to world peace.
我想祈\世界和平
To world peace.
敬世界和平
Amen.
阿T
- This is wonderful. - Didn't I tell you?
- 很好吃 - 我不是f^了幔
How do you know so much about Punxsutawney?
你怎N@Nt解普K塔尼？
I've spent a lot of time here.
我常待在@e
- Small town people are more real. - That's how I feel.
- 小居民在多了 - 那也是我的感X
Really? Would you like some white chocolate?
真的？想吃白巧克力幔
- Don't make me sick. - No white chocolate.
- e我f心了 - 不吃白巧克力
There is something familiar about this.
@感X好熟悉
- Do you ever have deja vu? - Didn't you just ask me that?
- 你有似曾相R的感X幔 - 你不是^幔
People place too much emphasis on their careers.
人太重事I了
I wish we could all live in the mountains at high altitude.
我希望人能住在高山上
That's where I see myself in five years.
我希望五年後能k到
- How about you? - I agree.
- 你呢？ - 我同意
I like to go with the flow, see where it leads me.
我喜g其自然，看怎
It's led you here.
Y果F在你成@
It's a million miles from where I started in college.
我]有W以致用
You weren't in broadcasting or journalism?
你不是念新或鞑サ幔
Believe it or not, I studied 19th-century French poetry.
信不信由你 我主修19世o法
What a waste of time.
真是浪Mrg
For someone else that would be an incredible waste of time.
e人碚f那非常浪Mrg
It was so bold of you to choose that. It's incredible.
你x衲穷I域真有勇 y以置信
You must be a very strong person.
你一定是意志很的人
People place too much emphasis on their careers.
人太重事I了
I wish we could all live in the mountains, at high altitudes.
我希望人能住在高山上
That's where I see myself in five years.
我希望五年後能k到
- How about you? - I agree.
- 你呢？ - 我同意
I like to go with the flow, see what happens.
我喜g其自然，看怎
It's gotten you here.
Y果你成F在@
It's a million miles from where I started in college.
我]有W以致用
You weren't in broadcasting or journalism?
你不是念新或鞑サ幔
Believe it or not, I studied 19th-century French poetry.
信不信由你 我主修19世o法
You speak French.
你f法Z
- I haven't done this since I was a kid. - Me neither.
- 我L大後就]玩^@ - 我也一
- It's fun. - It's good, clean fun.
- 很好玩 - 乾Q又好玩
I hope that one day I can do this with my own children.
希望有天能和我的孩子一起玩
Where did you get that?
哪e弄淼模
I went over to the snowman shop.
我到一家雪人商店
An assassin!
刺客！
I'll protect you, Your Majesty.
我保o你，陛下
I shall die for you! You shall not take her!
我槟愣死 你不得逞的
Find cover, my lady!
ふ已谧o，小姐
- Nice arm. - I'm getting some good ones.
- 臂力不e - 我G一些大的雪球
There's a boy. That's a boy. Good try.
那有一，G得不e
- Got him. - Help me.
- G中了 - 拉我一把
- What? - I'm amazed, and I'm not easily amazed.
- 怎樱 - 我好@，我不常@拥
- About what? - How you can start a day...
- 什N事？ - 一天_始r的期望…
with one kind of expectation and end up so completely different.
和最後的Y果居然完全不同
Do you like the way this day is turning out?
你喜g今天的Y果幔
I like it very much.
非常喜g
It's a perfect day. You couldn't plan a day like this.
今天很完美 @是人不出淼
You can. It just takes an awful lot of work.
可以，只是很花功夫
Come on in. I want to show you something.
M恚o你看|西
- I don't think I should. - I don't think you should either.
- 不太好吧 - 我想也是
That's why I'll show you one thing and kick you out. Just one minute.
所以看|西你就得走 一下子就好
It's just lovely.
好剀
Would you like to sit and stare at the fake fire?
想坐著看假t火幔
It's really a wonderful room.
@房g真棒
It is now.
到F在才棒
I don't know. I don't think we should do this.
我不知道，我不@N做
I don't either.
我想也是
On second thought, I think we should.
我考]之後，我是做
It's the perfect end to a perfect day.
@是完美一天的完美句c
It's a little fast for me.
我X得太快了
Me too.
我也是
Maybe I should go.
也S我走了
Where would you go?
你要去哪e？
Why? We've got a perfect fire.
槭颤N？ 我有完美的t火
I've got some French poetry here. Baudelaire.
我@e有一首法 是波德R的
I will read to you.
我念o你
I've got ice cream on the windowsill.
我的窗台上有冰淇淋
Hold on a minute.
等一下
- Rocky Road? - I love Rocky Road.
- 香草脆果巧克力？ - 我鬯肋@了
I thought so.
我想也是
You have to stay.
你得留下
I'm tired. We can see each other tomorrow.
我累了，我明天再面
Tonight. It's gotta be tonight.
今晚，一定要是今晚
- Really. - Just stay for awhile.
- 真的 - 待一喊
If you like it, stay for a while longer and awhile longer.
你芬獾脑，多待一
- Let's not spoil it. - I don't want to spoil it either.
- e搞砸了 - 我也不想
You know I can't stay with you.
你明白我不能留下砼隳
Why not? I love you.
槭颤N？我勰
You love me?
你畚遥
- You don't even know me. - I know you.
- 你根本不t解我 - 我t解你
I can't believe I fell for this.
我不敢相信自己信以檎
This whole day has just been one long setup.
@一整天都是陷阱
- It hasn't. - And I hate fudge.
- 不是 - 我痛恨e言
No white chocolate. No fudge.
]有白巧克力，]有e言
What are you doing? Are you making some kind of list?
你在做什N？ 你在列什N巫幔
Did you call my friends and ask what I like and what I don't like?
你有打我朋友 我喜g和不喜g什N幔
- Is this what love is for you? - This is real. This is love.
- @就是你所^的幔 - @是真的，@是
Stop saying that! You must be crazy.
ef了！你一定是了
I could never love someone like you. You only love yourself.
我^不凵夏氵@N人 你只勰阕约
That's not true. I don't even like myself. Give me another chance.
不Γ我甚至不喜g自己 再o我一次C
That's for making me care about you.
你@感情_子！
- I haven't done this since I was a kid. - Me neither.
- 我L大後就]再玩^ - 我也一
- It's fun. - Good, clean fun too.
- 很好玩 - 乾Q又好玩
That's what's missing in the world today.
今天世界缺乏的就是@
I can't wait to do this with my own children.
我等不及和自己的孩子一起玩
Golly, I want lots of kids!
天啊，我想要很多孩子！
I want to adopt. I want to have my own.
我要IB孩子，要自己生
I want foster kids. I got this at Snowman City.
我要收B小孩 我在雪人城找到的
Some kid threw a snowball at us!
有小孩ξG雪球
Come here! Let's have some fun!
^恚我好好玩玩！
I wish these were my own kids!
真希望他是我的孩子
Are any of you up for adoption?
你有人打算被IB幔
Here's a humdinger over here! Wasn't that great?
@e有很棒的ο 很好玩吧？
Stop it!
住手
Over here!
在@
Where have you been? You're missing all the fun.
你到哪去了？ 你e^好玩的|西了
You look terrible.
你的幼雍迷愀
What happened? Rough night?
怎N了？睡不好幔
Okay, campers, rise and shine.
快起床
Don't forget your booties because it's cold out there today.
e忘了b 今天外面很冷
It's cold out there every day.
外面每天都很冷
This country's largest lake, Chapala, is located near the city...
哪家其最大的恰帕拉湖 位於瓜_拉哈拉附近？
- Correct. - "Lakes and Rivers," 400.
- 答α - 湖泊c河流，四百元
Seneca is the largest of these lakes in West-Central New York.
~s州中西部哪湖群 其中最大的湖是塞尼加湖？
- What are the Finger Lakes? - Correct.
- 手指湖 - 答α
- That's amazing. - "Lakes and Rivers" for 600.
湖泊c河流，六百元
This South American lake drains into the smaller lake in Bolivia.
哪南美洲的湖流入 波利S更小的湖？
- What is Titicaca? - Correct.
- 的的喀喀湖 - 答α
- "Lakes and Rivers" for 1,000. - Milky colored...
- 湖泊c河流，一千元 - 因樵醋员河…
- from glacial clay... - What is the Rhone?
答案是隆河
Jim? The Rhone is good for $ 1,000.
吉姆？ 隆河，你@得一千元
- You are $500 off the lead. - Let's go to "Inventors" for 200.
- xI先有五百元 - 我xl明家，砂僭
This is pitiful.
真令人同情
A thousand people freezing their butts off, waiting to worship a rat.
一千人龅靡命 等著要崇拜一b老鼠
What a hype. Groundhog Day used to mean something in this town.
真是天大的_局 土苁蠊以前是e有意x的
They used to pull the hog out and eat it!
他以前把鼠拖出沓缘簦
You're hypocrites, all of you!
你全都是尉子！
You got a problem with what I'm saying?
你ξ业脑有意幔
Untie your tongue, and you come out here and talk.
嘴巴_，^碚f啊
Am I upsetting you, Princess?
我惹你不高d幔公主？
You want a prediction about the weather, you're asking the wrong Phil.
你想天 s到e的菲
I'll give you a winter prediction.
我湍Ay
It's gonna be cold...
天很冷…
it's gonna be gray...
天色很暗…
and it's gonna last you for the rest of your life.
你一子都那
Once again, the eyes of the nation have turned here to this...
每年在@r候 全目光都D移到
tiny village in western Pennsylvania.
@e州西部的小上
There is no way that this winter...
只要@只土苁 一直看到自己的影子
is ever going to end...
今年冬天…
as long as this groundhog keeps seeing his shadow.
就不Y束
I don't see any other way out.
我]k法了
He has to be stopped.
要有人阻止它
I have to stop him.
我得阻止它
Real good, Phil.
很好，菲
He's crazy.
他了
I'm worried. I think there's something really wrong with Phil.
我好心 菲真的出了}
There's a lot of things
菲真的很不
I've come to the end of me.
我已快完了
There's no way out now.
]有k法了
I just want you to remember we had a beautiful day together once.
我要你得 我曾共渡美好的一天
All right, little fella. Good job.
好了，小砘铮做的好
- He smiled at me. Did you see that? - I believe he did.
- 它ξ倚Γ看到]？ - 我相信它有
Okay, little fella. There you go.
小砘铮M去吧
Hi, mister. Something I can do you for?
先生，有什N事幔
What are you doing?
你在致铮
Jake, get the word out! Somebody kidnapped Phil!
芸耍快通知大家！ 有人架了菲！
We're going after him!
我去追他！
Why would anybody steal a groundhog?
怎N有人偷土苁竽兀
I can probably think of a couple of reasons. Pervert.
我想到可能原因 性B
- He must have just snapped! - This should be good.
- 他一定抓狂了 - @下可精彩了
What is he doing? What can he be thinking?
他在致铮克在想什N？
That's not bad for a quadruped.
λ哪_的游碚f算不e了
You gotta check your mirrors, just the side of your eye.
要看照後R
They're chasing us! Come on, make it fun!
他在追我！_快c！
Don't drive angry.
_e激
Hot dog! There's no way out except the way we came in. We got him now!
@e]e的路了，逮到他了！
- What is he doing? - I don't know.
- 他在致铮 - 不知道
If you gotta shoot, aim high. I don't wanna hit the groundhog.
要_就瞄高一c e打到土苁罅
We mustn't keep our public waiting.
不能^等太久
It's show time.
好蛏隽
All right, on me, Larry, in three!
好，瑞，倒3秒…
Two, one.
2、1
He might be okay.
他f不定]事
Probably not now.
@下子大概完了
Nuts.
混蛋
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
睡得好幔康{先生？
Would you like some toast?
想吃土司幔
- What's going on? - My God.
- 怎N回事？ - 天啊
That's him.
是他
He was a really great guy.
他真的是好人
I really liked him a lot.
我真的很喜g他
I'm sorry. What was that again?
什N，你f什N？
- I'm a god! - You're a god?
- 我是神！ - 你是神？
I'm a god. I'm not the God, I don't think.
我是神，但不是上帝
Because you survived a car wreck?
只因槟丬]死？
You ready to order?
要c餐了幔
I didn't just survive a wreck. I wasn't just blown up yesterday.
我不只是]死 或只是昨天被炸死
I have been stabbed, shot, poisoned...
我被刺、、毒害…
frozen, hung, electrocuted...
鏊馈⒌跛馈㈦
- and burned. - Really?
- 被火 - 真的？
Every morning I wake up fine, not a dent in the fender.
每天早上醒s毫o
- I am an immortal. - Special today is blueberry waffles.
- 我不死 - 今日特餐是{莓
Why are you telling me this?
你f@些致铮
Because I want you to believe in me.
因槲乙你相信我
You're not a god. Believe me. This is 12 years of Catholic school talking.
你不是神，相信我 我上^12年天主教W校
I could come back if you're not ready.
我可以等一下再湍泓c
How do you know I'm not a god?
你怎N知道我不是神？
Please! Because it's not possible!
拜！
- I'll come back. - Doris!
- 我等一下再 - 桃莉
This is Doris. Her brother-in-law, Carl, owns this diner.
@是桃莉，她姐夫卡是老
She's worked here since she was 17. She wants to see Paris before she dies.
她17q就在@e上班 她希望死前能到巴黎一[
- Boy, would I! - What are you doing?
- 天啊，我好想去 - 你在致铮
- Debbie Kleiser and her fiance, Fred. - Do I know you?
- 黛比和她的未婚夫佛瑞 - 我JR你幔
They're supposed to be married this afternoon, but Debbie is reconsidering.
他本斫裉煜挛缫Y婚 但是黛比要重新考]
- What? - Lovely ring.
- 什N？ - 好美的戒指
This is Bill who's been a waiter for three years...
@是比，他服丈三年了
since he left Penn State and had to get work.
因樗大W不念了，需要工作
He likes the town, paints toy soldiers, and he's gay.
他喜g@e，玩具兵 是同性
I am.
]e
This is Gus. He hates his life here and wishes he'd stayed in the Navy.
@是Z斯，他@e的生活 希望能留在海服役
I could have retired on half pay after 20 years.
20年後我退伍能I半薪
Is this some kind of trick?
@是什N幔
Maybe the real God uses tricks. Maybe He's not omnipotent.
也S上帝耍 也S他不是f能的
He's just been around so long, He knows everything.
他只是在我身很久了 所以什N都知道
- Who's that? - This is Tom.
- 那是l？ - @是姆
He worked in the coal mine till they closed it down.
他是V工，一直做到V坑P]
- Her? - Alice.
- 她呢？ - 劾蚪z
She came from Ireland as a baby and lived in Erie most of her life.
rm^ 一子都住在艾e
- He's right. - Nancy.
- 他f的 - 南茜
She works in the dress shop and makes chipmunk noises when she gets excited.
她在服b店上班 d^rl出花栗鼠的音
- It's true. - How do you know these people?
- 是真的 - 你怎NJR@些人？
I know everything. In five seconds, a waiter will drop a tray of dishes.
我什N都知道，5秒後 有服丈打破P子
- Five, four, three, two, one. - This is nuts.
- 5、4、3、2、1 - 太狂了
That's enough.
蛄
- Do you know me too? - I know all about you.
- 你也t解我幔 - 我t解你的一切
You like producing, but you're hoping for more than Channel 9 Pittsburgh.
你喜gu作目 s不希望只待在第9l道
Everyone knows that.
@大家都知道
You like boats, but not the ocean.
你喜g船，s不喜g海
You go to a mountain lake in the summer with your family.
夏天你跟家人 到山上的一座湖
There's a long, wooden dock and a boathouse...
那e有LL的木船渠 有一g船
with boards missing from the roof...
屋的木板都不了
and a place you used to crawl underneath to be alone.
有一你爬下去 的地方
You're a sucker for French poetry and rhinestones.
你喜g法文和R因石
You're very generous.
你很大方
You're kind to strangers and children.
你δ吧人和小孩都很和善
And when you stand in the snow, you look like an angel.
你站在雪地e 就像天使一
How are you doing this?
你怎Nk到的？
I wake up every day right here...
我f了 我每天在普K塔尼醒
in Punxsutawney, and it's always February 2.
每天都是2月2日
There's nothing I can do about it.
我]k法改@情r
If you still doubt me...
如果你岩傻脑
in ten seconds...
10秒之後
Larry will come through that door and take you away from me...
瑞M你走
but you can't let him.
但你不能他你走
Please believe me. You've got to believe me.
相信我，一定要相信我
You ready? We better get going if we're going to stay ahead of the weather.
好了]？趁天庾那摆s快走
What's that?
(趁天庾那摆s快走) 那是什N？
Maybe it really is happening.
也S真的l生了
How else could you know so much?
不然你怎N知道那N多？
There is no way. I'm not that smart.
不可能，我]那N明
Maybe I should spend the day with you...
也S今天我跟你在一起
as an objective witness, just to see what happens.
客^目粽撸看l生什N事
This sounds like a science project.
起砗孟窨W
Concentrate. You gotta want it.
Ｐ囊稽c，GM去
It's more in the wrist than the finger. It's just gotta...
重c在手腕，不在手指
Be the hat! Come on! Go!
GM帽子e，G！
It would take me a year to get good at this.
我要花一年才能W
Six months. Four to five hours a day, and you'd be an expert.
六月，每天四到五小r 你就能成＜
Is this what you do with eternity?
你@哟虬l永a的rg幔
Now you know.
F在你知道了
That's not the worst part.
@不是最糟的
What's the worst part?
最糟的是什N？
The worst part is that tomorrow you will have forgotten all about this...
最糟的是明天你忘掉@一切
and you'll treat me like a jerk again.
又把我混蛋
- It's all right. I am a jerk. - You're not.
- ]PS，我是混蛋 - 你不是
It doesn't make any difference.
]什N差e
I've killed myself so many times, I don't even exist anymore.
我已自⒑芏啻瘟 我早就不存在了
Sometimes I wish I had a thousand lifetimes.
有r我倒希望我有上千子
I don't know, Phil. Maybe it's not a curse.
我不知道，菲 或S@不是{咒
It just depends on how you look at it.
端看你如何看待它
Gosh, you're an upbeat lady!
天啊，你真是酚^的女人
- It's been a really nice day for me. - Me too.
- 我X得今天很愉快 - 我也是
Maybe, if it's not too boring, we could do it again sometime.
如果不算太o聊的 改天我可以再硪淮
I hope so.
希望如此
You're still here.
你在
I thought you were supposed to disappear or I was or something!
我以槟消失 或我消失
Not until 6:00.
要等到6c
You rat!
你@小人！
I never said midnight.
我]f^在午夜
- You knew I was waiting for midnight! - Does this mean you're gonna leave?
- 你知道我在等午夜 - 你要走了幔
Good.
好
I'm sorry.
Σ黄
It's all right. You can fall asleep.
]PS，你可以睡
I promise I won't touch you, much.
我保C不碰你…太多
That's all right. I'm not tired.
]PS，我不累
What were you saying?
你f什N？
I think the last thing that you heard was...
你到最後一句是
"Only God can make a tree."
「只有上帝能造洹
Really?
真的？
What I wanted to say was...
我想f的是
I think you're the kindest, sweetest, prettiest person...
你是我一生中^ 最善良、wN…
I've ever met in my life.
最美的人
I've never seen anyone...
我]^…
that's nicer to people than you are.
比你待人更好的人
The first time I saw you...
第一次到你
something happened to me.
我就有N奇妙的感X
I never told you, but...
我]告V^你，但…
I knew that I wanted to hold you as hard as I could.
我知道我要oo地肀你
I don't deserve someone like you.
我配不上你
But if I ever could...
但如果可以
I swear I would love you...
我l誓我勰
for the rest of my life.
一生一世
Did you say something?
你才f什N？
Good night.
晚安
Who wants coffee? Get it while it's hot.
l要咖啡？趁岷
Thanks, Phil.
x了，菲
- Larry? Skim milk, two sugars. - Thanks, Phil.
- 瑞？脂牛奶，沙滋 - x了，菲
- Pastry? - We're just setting up.
- c心？ - 我在架C器
Take your pick.
自己挑
Thanks. Raspberry. Great.
xx，覆盆子，好棒
I was just talking with Buster Green, the head groundhog honcho.
我跟巴斯特^ 他是活又鬓k人
He said if we set up over here, we might get a better shot.
他fC器架在那 拍到比^好的R^
- What do you think? - Sounds good.
- 你X得如何？ - 好像不e
What do you think?
你X得呢？
Let's go for it.
我^去吧
- Good work. - Maybe we'll get lucky.
- 做的好 - 我\夂
Let me help you with the heavy stuff.
我湍惆崞鞑
You got your coffee. I'll get it.
你喝你的咖啡，我
We never talk. Do you have kids?
我]聊^天 你有孩子幔
I'd like a piano lesson, please.
我想上琴n
I'm with a student now. If you come back tomorrow, I can squeeze you in.
我F在有W生 明天再恚我湍惆才趴纯
I kind of want to get started. I could give you $1,000.
我想R上_始 我可以o你一千元
Come on in.
M
Good morning! Off to see the groundhog?
早安！要去看土苁幔
You think it will be an early spring?
你想今年是早春幔
"Winter slumbering in the open air...
「冬天在敉獬了」
wears on his smiling face...
「展_笑」
a dream of spring."
「春天的簟
How's she look?
雕得怎N樱
- Great. - Thank you.
- 很漂亮 - xx
Did you know he could ice sculpt?
你知道他冰雕幔
Not bad. You say this is your first lesson?
不e，你f @是你第一次上n？
My father was a piano mover.
我爸^琴搬\工人
I thought it was you.
菲康{？我就知道是你
I have missed you so much.
我好想你
I don't know where you're headed, but can you call in sick?
我不知道你要去哪 但你能病假幔
I gotta get going.
我得走了
It's good to see you.
到你真好
Hello, father.
老爹
Let's get you someplace warm.
我找暖和的地方
Remember me?
得我幔
Excuse me, sir. Are you the one who brought the old man in?
抱歉，先生 是你那位老先生M淼幔
How is he?
他怎N樱
He just passed away.
他^世了
What did he die of?
死因是什N？
He was just old. It was just his time.
年o大，r候到了
- I want to see his chart. Excuse me. - Sir!
- 我要看他的病v，Σ黄 - 先生！
You can't come in here.
你不能M去
This is a restricted area.
@是管制^
Where's the chart?
病v呢？
Sometimes people just die.
人死的
Not today.
今天不行
It's hard down there at the bottom.
碗底吃不到
- Here you go. - Thank you.
- 砹 - xx
Come on, Dad! Come on, Pop!
起戆。老爹
When Chekhov saw the long winter...
人契X夫淼竭@e 渡^漫漫的L冬
he saw a winter bleak and dark and bereft of hope.
他下刺骨寒冷的冬季 人y以抵
Yet we know that winter is just another step in the cycle of life.
但是@只是 人生o_始的D折
But standing here among the people of Punxsutawney...
在@e，普K塔尼的居民
and basking in the warmth of their hearths and hearts...
以他的喜泛崆
I couldn't imagine a better fate...
使@一季漫漫L冬…
than a long and lustrous winter.
D成充M著感恩cS收
From Punxsutawney, it's Phil Connors.
我是菲康{ 在普K塔尼的
So long.
再
Very nice speech, Phil.
f得很棒，菲
- Thank you. - Thanks.
- xx - x了
- How was that for you two? - Man, you touched me.
- 你X得怎N樱 - 我被你感恿
- Thanks, Larry. - Thank you.
- x了，瑞 - xx
I gotta go.
我得走了
That was surprising. I didn't know you were so versatile.
真令人@ ]想到你@N有才A
I surprise myself sometimes.
有r我自己也很@
Would you like to get some coffee?
想喝c咖啡幔
I'd love to. Can I have a rain check? I've got some errands to run.
我很想，改天好幔 我有事要做
Hold it, fella!
抓好了，小子
What do you say?
你f什N？
You little brat. You have never thanked me!
小鬼，你矶]xx我
I'll see you tomorrow, maybe!
也S明天吧
- Now what? - You've totaled it.
- 怎N了 - 全被你Я
It's only a flat tire. Now just be patient. Just cool it!
只是爆胎而已，eo
- It's an earthquake! - It's not an earthquake!
- 是地震！ - 不是地震！
What is it?
怎N回事？
Thank you, young man.
xx你，年p人
It's nothing. I had the tire and the jack.
]什N 我好有胎和千斤
Just be comfortable. Be a minute.
坐好，R上就可以修好
Who is that?
他是l？
Must be from the motor club.
一定是修S的
- My God! He's having a heart attack! - What should I do?
- 天啊，他心K病l作了！ - 怎Nk？
- Call an ambulance, a lawyer, a doctor! - Mom, I don't think he's breathing!
- 叫救o、律、t生！ - ，他]有呼吸了
I think that did it.
]事了
If you're gonna eat steak, get some sharper teeth.
想吃牛排 就需要b尖一c的牙X
- Enjoy your lunch. - Thank you.
- 慢用 - xx
Who was that? I'm fine.
他是l？我]事了
- Are you sure? - Oh, yes. Eat.
- 真的幔 - Γ吃吧
People just don't understand what is involved in this.
人不懂其中W妙
This is an art form.
@是一Ng形式
You know, I think most people just think that...
大部份的人以椤
I hold the camera and point it at stuff.
我拿z影Cχ|西拍
There is a lot more to it than just that.
其不只是那
Would you be at all interested in seeing the inside of the van?
有d趣看上的|西幔
You know, I really have to get back to the party.
我真的要回派θチ
Great idea. I'll go with you. Let me just drop a tip here.
好主意，我跟你去 我留一c小M
We were just going to the party.
我要去⒓优
- You going? - Sounds like fun.
- 你要去幔 - 好像很好玩
Maybe we should call Phil.
我通知菲
- Isn't he good? - He's great!
- 他很棒吧？ - 棒呆了！
He's my student.
他是我的W生
I'm so proud.
我好傲
Thank you.
xx
Welcome to our party.
g迎光R我的派
- I didn't know you could play like that. - I'm versatile.
- 我不知道你得那N好 - 我多才多
It's that nice, young man from the motor club.
修S的年p人，你真好心
- Thank you again. - It's nothing, ladies.
- 再次xx你 - ]什N，女士
He's the fastest jack in Jefferson County.
他是本郡幼髯羁斓男捃手
What was that all about?
@是怎N回事？
I really don't know. They've been hitting on me all night.
我真的不知道 她一整晚都在吃我的豆腐
There you are.
你在@e啊
I never thanked you properly for what you did for Buster.
我]好好xx你救了巴斯特
He would have choked for sure.
他本硪欢噎死的
He may have. He was trying to swallow a whole cow.
可能，他想吞下一整l牛呢
- I owe you one, buddy. - Hang onto him, dear. He's a real find.
- 我欠你一次，老兄 - 好好把握，他是y得的好人
- What did you do today? - Same old, same old.
- 你今天做了什N事？ - 和平常一
Excuse me.
Σ黄
Fred, how was the wedding?
佛瑞，婚Y好幔
I just wanted to thank you for making Debbie go through with it.
我要xx你黛比想通了
All I did was fan the flame of her passion for you.
我只是激l了她δ愕崆
You are the best.
你最棒了
Rita, this is Debbie and Fred Kleiser.
塔，@是黛比和佛瑞
- Here you go, kids. Congratulations. - What is this?
- 拿去，恭喜你 - @是什N？
No way!
不吧
Wrestlemania!
⒂^狂摔角！
How did you know? We're gonna be in Pittsburgh anyway!
你怎N知道？ 反正我都要去匹堡
- Thank you! You're a real pal! - This is the best!
- xx，你真蚺笥眩 - @才是最棒的
- I don't understand. - I guess not.
- 我不懂 - 我想也是
How does everyone know you? You only come here once a year.
大家怎N都JR你？ 你一年才硪淮
You seem like the most popular person in town.
你好像是城e最受g迎的人
Excuse me. Dr. Connors?
Σ黄穑康{t生幔
I want to thank you for fixing Felix's back.
我要xx你治好菲力的背
He can even help around the house again.
他又能整理花@了
I'm sorry to hear that, Felix.
真z憾，菲力
"Dr. Connors"?
「康{t生」？
It's kind of an honorary title.
那是一Nsu^
- What is going on? - I really don't know.
- 怎N回事？ - 我真的不知道
There is something going on with you.
你一定在搞什N鬼
Would you like the long version or the short one?
你想完整版是饪s版？
Let's start with the short and go from there.
先饪s版_始
Okay, folks. Attention.
好，各位注意
Time for the big bachelor auction. You all know the rules.
拍u紊hrg到了 你都知道t
All the eligible bachelors come down in front...
有Y格的紊h到前面
and you ladies bid on them!
女士出r
You get to do whatever you want with them. No questions asked!
你可以和他做任何事 不准}
I don't want to know about it, as long as it's legal!
只要合法 我不想知道你做什N事
Get out your pocketbooks and remember, it's all for charity!
X包拿出 得@是慈善活
What are you doing down here? Go on. Get up there.
你在@e致铮可咸ㄈグ
I got ten bucks that says you're mine!
我有十KX，你是我的了
- Buster, I got your first victim. - Come up here!
- 我找到第一受害者 - 菲康{，上戆桑
All right! What am I bid for this fine specimen?
好，@位良男士 出r多少？
Five dollars!
5KX
The bidding has begun at five dollars.
5元起跳
- Ten dollars! - Fifteen!
- 10元 - 15元
- Twenty! - Twenty-five!
- 20 - 25
- Thirty! - Thirty-five!
- 30 - 35
- Forty! - Forty-five!
- 40 - 45
- Fifty! - Fifty-five!
- 50 - 55
- Sixty! - I'm bid sixty. Do I hear more?
- 60 - 60，有更高的幔
Three hundred and thirty-nine dollars and eighty-eight cents!
339元8毛8！
We can't accept any more bids. That's sold...
我不接受出r了 就uo…
to the little lady for $339.88!
出339元8毛8的女士
Congratulations.
恭喜
Okay, bachelors! Who's next?
紊h，下一是l？
All right! What am I bid for this guy?
好，各位出r多少？
Do I hear a buck and a half?
有人出1K半幔
Anybody?
有]有？
- Seventy-five cents? - I bid two bits!
- 7毛5？ - 我出2毛5
Sold to the lady for twenty-five cents!
出2毛5的女士得
I got him!
我得肆
Phil Connors! I thought that was you!
菲康{，我就知道是你
This is Ned Ryerson, my new insurance agent.
@是尼德R森 我新的保Uo人
I'll say!
是啊
I have not seen this guy for 20 years.
我有20年]到@砘锪
He comes to me and buys whole life, term, uniflex...
他跟我I了所有的保U K身U、我浑U
fire, theft, auto, dental, health...
火U、`IU、汽U 牙XU、健康U
with the optional death and dismemberment plan, water damage.
加上意外死亡、解雇U 和水碾U
This is the best day of my life.
今天是我@子最棒的一天
Mine too.
我也是
- Where are we going? - Let's not spoil it.
- 我要去哪？ - e襞萘
I got that!
我懂了
- Why can't I look? - Because you bother me a lot.
- 我槭颤N不能看？ - 因槟我分心
I'm getting cold. How much longer do I have to sit here?
我很冷，要坐多久？
I'm just giving you your money's worth. You paid top dollar for me.
我要你值回票r 你出最高r得
I think you were a bargain.
我J槟闶俏锍所值
Sweet of you to say. You're probably right.
你@Nf真好 也S你fα
- Is it finished yet? - Almost.
- 完成了]？ - 快好了
I still have to put cherry syrup on top and then we can eat it.
我要淋烟姨{才能吃
Come on! I'm freezing!
快c！我快鏊懒耍
One second. All right. Let me turn toward the light.
等一下，好了 我把它D向艄
It's amazing.
不可思h
It's beautiful.
好漂亮
- How did you do that? - I know your face so well...
- 你怎N做到的？ - 你的我非常熟悉
I could have done it with my eyes closed.
我能]著眼睛做
It's lovely. I don't know what to say.
好漂亮，我不知道f什N
I do.
我知道
No matter what happens tomorrow...
o明天l生什N事
or for the rest of my life...
或者往後的生命中l生什N事
I'm happy now because I love you.
我F在都很快 因槲勰
I think I'm happy too.
我也很快
- Please, not again. - That is a great song!
- 拜，e又砹 - 那首歌很棒！
- It's not! - Don't listen to this man...
- 才怪 - e@砘锏摹
It's too early.
F在太早了
Something is different.
有c不一
Good or bad?
好事是氖拢
Anything different is good...
只要不一泳褪呛檬
but this could be real good.
不^@真的很好
Why are you here?
你怎N在@e？
I bought you. I own you.
我I了你，你是我的
You said stay, so I stayed.
你叫我留下，我就留下
I said stay, so you stayed?
我叫你留下你就留下？
I can't even make a collie stay.
B小狗狗都不我的
I gotta check something.
我去看|西
Stay.
留下
They're gone!
他不了
They're all gone!
他全都不了
- Do you know what today is? - What?
- 知道今天是什N幔 - 什N？
Today is tomorrow.
今天就是明天
It happened.
真的是@
- You're here. - I'm here.
- 你在@e - 我在@e
Why weren't you like this last night? You just fell sleep.
你昨晚怎N不像@幼樱 你睡著了
It was the end of a very long day.
昨晚是漫L一天的Y束
Is there anything I can do for you today?
今天我能湍阕鍪颤N事幔
I'm sure I can think of something.
我一定想出事情o你做
It's so beautiful!
好漂亮
Let's live here.
我住在@e吧
We'll rent to start.
先租一g房子再f